Ernest D. Peterson

Web Developer

Pensacola, FL Phone: 601-307-4377 Email Website GitHub LinkedIn

My creative nature and my love for technology has lead me to switch careers. My experiences from starting my own business and managing loads, equipment and personnel gives me a good foundation for teamwork and web development.

Skills

HTML 5 | Javascript/Jquery | CSS 3 | Jasmine Testing | KnockoutJS Framework/Library | Small Business Owner

Projects

My Website 2017

- Used HTML, JavaScript/Jquery and CSS to make a fully functioning web site.
- Practical application of the skills learned from Udacity Front End Web Progam.

Neighborhood Map for Udacity

2018

- A challenging project integrating API, JavaScript and KnockoutJS framework.
- Created a Google maps page showing POI and retrieving reviews and street views of locations

Jasmine Testing for Udacity

2018

- An introduction to test driven development.
- Learned to write effective tests using the Jasmine JavaScript testing framework.

Experience

Driver | Airgas | Star, MS

7/2008 - Current

- Driving and managing multiple deliveries a week for over 9 years successfully and safely.
- Filling in at other locations when needed, providing a model later termed "fast team" by corporate.

Owner/Operator | Peterson Transportation | Seminary, MS

4/2003 - 6/2008

- Started my own trucking company.
- Managed leasing, loads, scheduling, bookkeeping and DOT compliance.

Manager/Driver | Sanderson Farms| Collins, MS

11/1993 - 10/1999

- Managed a spray crew of 4.
- Became a driver to help get the live haul division started and substituted for managers needing time off.

Education

Udacity | Online

Front End Web Developer Nano-Degree

2018

O'Reilly School of Technology | Online

University of Phoenix | Online

•	Linux Sysems Administration	2015
•	Introduction to Database Administration	2014

CompTIA A+ and Networking +

2014